你们好
"Hello.
我是严肃深沉的理查德·卡塞尔
I'm serious and brooding Richard Castle."
我是友好  平易近人
"And I am friendly, accessible,
粗犷帅气的理查德·卡塞尔
ruggedly handsome Richard Castle."
老爸
Wow, dad.
你的头还能再大点吗
Could your head get any bigger?
能怪我吗
Can you blame me?
我要接受坡之笔成就奖啊
I'm accepting the Poe's Pen Career Achievement Award.
这是犯罪小说家的最高荣誉
It is the biggest honor a mystery writer can get.
我要加入伟人的万神殿
I am joining the pantheon of greats
加入那些我一向敬仰的人
to whose heights I have always aspired.
用哪个大头
So which big head?
我喜欢粗犷帅气的大笑脸
Uh, I like the ruggedly handsome, smiling giant you.
我喜欢严肃深沉的大脸
I like the serious, brooding giant you.
好吧  母亲
All right, mother.
你来打破平局吧
You are the tie-breaker.
下周的仪式上该选哪张
Which of these should be hanging behind me
挂在我身后
at the ceremony next week?
亲爱的  你知道我从不偏颇
Darling, you know I refuse to play favorites.
我对我儿子的两个大脸的爱是一样的
I love both of my son's big heads equally.
好了  我要去见个朋友了
All right. I am off to meet a friend of mine
这位朋友的父亲刚刚去世了
whose father just passed away.
玛莎  我很遗憾
Oh, Martha, I am so sorry.
没事的
Oh, no, no. Don't be.
他活得很精彩
He had a r-rich, full life.
更重要的是  他在切尔西有栋租金管制的阁楼
And, more importantly, he has a rent-controlled loft in Chelsea,
我如果做得巧妙  或许能搞到手
which, if I play my cards right, could be mine.
再见了
Bye.
这就是我们都喜欢的"死亡即机遇"的精神
Well, there's the "death as opportunity" spirit we all love.
看来我们自己也遇到机遇了
Oh, looks like we have an opportunity of our own.
我们出发吧
Let's head out.
我们待会儿再考虑脸的事
We'll go head-to-head later.
懂我意思吗
See where I'm heading?
我拿了奖  你要申请做警监
You know, with this award, you going for captain,
我们或许能成为纽约的新权贵夫妇
we could be New York's newest power couple.
卡塞尔  别触霉头啊
Oh, Castle, don't jinx iit.
我的考试结果还没出来呢
I haven't even gotten my exam results back yet.
你肯定能行的
You, you aced it.
不  是那个心脏被斧子砍中的家伙
No, man. It was that guy with the ax in his heart.
他在躺椅上流血致死
He bled out in the barcalounger.
我们还喊他"苍蝇之王"呢  记得吗
We called him "Lord of the Flies," remember?
不不  你错了  兄弟
No, no, no. You're wrong, bro.
是宠物店老板被妻子喂了狗那个
It was the pet-shop owner whose wife fed him to the dogs.
你们吵什么呢
What are you guys fighting about?
蒙哥马利警监10年前的今天
Uh, the first case that Captain Montgomery
第一次让我们做搭档查的案子
partnered us on 10 years ago today.
是吗  今天是你们的纪念日啊
Really? It's your manniversary?
我居然都没给你们准备礼物
And I didn't get you anything.
还有时间哦
There's still time.
你们是12分局的
You the folks from the 12th?
我是柯林斯骑警
I'm trooper Collins.
多谢你们能来到辖区之外
Thanks for coming out of your jurisdiction.
被害人是个无名氏
Our victim's a Jane Doe.
看来她是在林中遭遇攻击
It appears she was attacked in the woods
一直被追到大路上
and chased onto the road,
被车撞死了
where she was hit by that truck.
由于袭击的关系
Because of the assault,
我们将此案列为凶杀
we're classifying the death as a homicide.
知道她是从哪过来的吗
Any idea where she was coming from?
这里是州狩猎场
It's state game land.
方圆数里无人家
Not a house for miles.
-尸体上有身份证吗  -没有
- Any I.D. on the body? - No.
指纹也查了  没收录在案过
And we ran her prints, but they're not on file.
我们已经派出队伍搜索林子了
We've got our teams out there searching the woods,
但我们在她胸罩里找到了这个
but we found these tucked into her bra.
50块  门卡  现金收据
$50 bill, key card, and a cash receipt.
是城里一家咖啡店的  昨天开据的
From a coffee shop in the city, dated yesterday.
这门卡看着像酒店的
This card looks like a hotel key.
但不是这一带的酒店
But it's not from anywhere around here.
我们认为她可能是住在城里的
We think maybe she was staying in the city.
我们希望你们能帮忙查清她的身份
We were hoping you could help us track down who she is
以及她为什么会在这里
and what she was doing here.
嗯  当然
Yeah, of course.
柯林斯骑警
Trooper Collins?
她脸上的伤痕
These carvings on her face?
十字吗
The crosses?
很诡异吧
Freaky, right?
我们认为她大概是在逃离对她做下了那种事的人
We think she was maybe running from whoever did that.
看上去像是某种仪式
They look ritualistic.
是啊  还有更怪的
Yeah. And it gets freakier.
卡车撞上姑娘的时候
Just as that trucker hit the girl,
他说看到林子里冒出个东西来
he says he saw something emerge from the woods.
什么东西
Some thing?
戴面具的黑影
A dark figure wearing a mask.
什么样的面具
What kind of mask?
他吓得不轻  我们就没逼问
He was pretty shaken, so we didn't press.
等他接受过救治我们再去录完整的口供
We'll get a full statement from him once he's been treated.
他人呢
Where is he?
在伍德伯里的医院
At the hospital in Woodbury.
失陪  柯林斯骑警  讲
Excuse me. Trooper Collins. Go.
我们得跟那个司机谈谈
We need to talk to that driver.
我想刹车的
I tried to stop. I did.
但她实在是突然就蹿了出来
But she just came out of nowhere.
沃特斯先生  骑警
Mr. Walters, the trooper
-说你看到了林子里的什么东西  -是的
- said you saw something in the woods. - Yeah.
看上去简直不像真的
It almost didn't seem real...
像是个鬼一般
Like it was some kind of ghost.
特别吓人
Freaky as all hell.
能描述一下吗
Can you describe it?
它穿了件深色的破外衣
It wore a dark ragged coat
戴着面具  像是张娃娃脸
with a mask like a doll's face.
像是瓷娃娃吗
Like porcelain?
对
Yeah.
是白的  眼睛的地方是黑的
It was white, with black where the eyes should have been.
有什么印记吗
Were there markings on it?
-有  -什么样的
- Yeah. - Like what?
像是眼睛流下的眼泪
Like streaked teardrops coming from the eyes.
脸是
Uh, and the... the face, it was, uh...
被两道黑线分割开  像个十字
Bisected with two black lines, like a cross.
是啊
Yeah.
你怎么知道
How'd you know that?
卡塞尔  怎么回事
Castle, what's going on?
是真的
It was real.
什么是真的
What was real?
贝克特  我见过那个面具
Beckett, I've seen that mask before.
这是卡车司机画的草图
The sketch is from the truck driver.
你愿意谈谈吗
You ready to talk about it?
那年我11岁
I was 11 years old.
我妈跟皮蓬团去做巡演了
Uh, my mother was touring with "Pippin."
我在新罕布什尔
I was in New Hampshire,
待在一个同学家
staying with the family of a classmate
跟他们一起过总统日的周末
for presidents' day weekend.
他们家旁边有几百亩的国有森林
Their home abutted a few hundred acres of state forest
叫"霍兰德森林"
called Hollander's woods.
大人们让我们绝不能单独进那林子
We were told never to go into the woods alone.
越是有人告诉你别去  你就越会想办法去
Somebody told you not to, so you had to do it anyway.
我走了好几个小时
I walked for hours.
我很冷  还彻底迷了路
I was cold, completely lost.
就是那时候  我看到了他
And that's when I saw him --
一个穿着黑衣的影子  跪在地上
a figure clad in black, kneeling.
过了一小会儿  他离开了
And after a few moments, he left.
然后我就看到她躺在地上
And that's when I saw her on the ground.
她
"Her"?
一具尸体
A body.
我这辈子见过的第一具尸体
First body I ever saw.
她的喉咙被撕开了
Her throat had been slit,
跟这次一样的符号
and those same symbols
被刻在她的额头和脸颊上
were carved into her forehead and her cheeks.
我碰了碰她的手臂
I touched her arm.
我还记得当时在想  真凉啊
I remember thinking how cold it was.
敢把你今天看到的事告诉任何人
Tell anyone what you've seen here today,
我会找到你  宰了你
and I'll find you and kill you.
明白吗
Do you understand?
滚
Go!
你觉得他为什么会放了你
Why do you think he let you live?
我不知道
I don't know.
我一直等到返回城里
I waited till I got back to the city
就用公用电话报了警
to call the police from a pay phone.
我太害怕了  不敢让警方知道我是谁
I was too scared to let them know who I was.
那女孩是谁
And who was the girl?
奇怪的就是这个
That's just the thing.
他们带着寻尸犬搜索了整片树林
They searched the woods with cadaver dogs.
完全没找到任何尸体
They never found a body.
所以你也一直不知道她是谁
So you never figured out who she was?
我查过当地的报纸
I checked local papers.
那附近没人被报失踪
No one in the area had been reported missing.
等我长大了点  我还查了失踪人口
When I got older, I checked with missing persons,
甚至是联调局的数据库
even the FBI database,
想找到任何跟她特征一致的人
for anyone matching her description
或任何涉及到这些符号或那面具的凶案
or any crimes involving those symbols or that mask,
但一无所获
but there was nothing.
就好像那事从未发生过
It's like it never happened.
后来  我自己也开始怀疑是否真有其事了
And after a while, I started to wonder if it had.
在树林里的那天  凯特
That day in the woods, kate --
那就是我开始写犯罪小说的原动力
that's why I do what I do.
我被驱使着解开一个个谜团故事
I'm driven to figure out the story
是因为那件事我一直没能弄清
because I could never figure out that one.
这事你以前怎么从来没跟我说过
Why didn't you ever tell me this before?
可能因为我不希望它是真的吧
I think I didn't want it to be real.
可它是真的
But it is real.
他是真实存在的
He's real.
他以前杀过人
He killed before,
现在他又要开杀戒了
and he just tried to kill again.
我问了霍兰德森林附近的警局
I checked with the police department near Hollander's woods.
他们的记录显示的确有一通电话
Their logs do show that they received a call
于83年2月举报有尸体
in February of '83 reporting a body.
但由于搜查一无所获  他们认为只是恶作剧
But after coming up empty, they assumed it was a prank.
好吧  那联调局的数据库呢
Okay, what about the FBI Database?
近30年内没有任何袭击或谋杀案
There's been no other occurrences in the past 30 years
出现过这种手法
of any assaults or murders with this MO.
贝克特  卡塞尔说的那件事
Beckett, this thing that Castle says happened,
已经过去几十年了
it was decades ago.
他真的确定吗
Is he really sure about this?
我从没见他这么坚定过
As sure as I've ever seen him.
那么  我们的无名女尸
So, our jane doe --
咖啡店的收据有什么发现吗
anything on that coffee-shop receipt?
有  有一个咖啡师记得见过死者
Yeah, a barista there remembered seeing our victim.
她不是常客
She wasn't a regular,
但最近几天她来过好几次
but she had been in several times in the past few days.
有人跟她一起吗
Was anyone with her?
没有  她都是一个人来的
No. She came in alone.
她总是点好饮品  找个座位
She'd get her drink, take a seat,
然后花好几个小时盯着窗外
and spend hours staring out the window.
好吧  不如我们找人去周围问问吧
Okay, why don't we set up a canvass of the neighborhood?
也许有人知道她是谁
Maybe someone there knows who she is.
过了这么多年
After all these years,
你真觉得会是同一个凶手吗
do you really think it could be the same killer?
要找到他才能知道答案了
We won't know until we find him.
记得我们在死者身上找到的门卡吗
That key card that we found on the victim?
是皇后区外一家可延期汽车旅馆的
It was tracked to an extended-stay motel out in Queens.
她付的现金
She paid cash for the room.
没有出示身份证
Didn't present an I.D.
登记名是简·史密斯
Registered as Jane Smith.
我猜不是真名
Not her real name, I'm guessing.
那我们还是不知道她是谁
So we still don't know who she is.
-她入住的时候有开车吗  -没有
- Did she have a car when she checked in? - No.
她打车来的
Cab dropped her off.
也就是说有人把她带去了树林
Which means someone took her to those woods.
她在这里待了多久
How long has she been staying here?
两周左右
About two weeks.
埃斯波  查查这些抽屉
Espo, check the drawers.
看能不能找到什么来确定死者身份
See if we can find anything to I.D. our victim.
照片  都是同一个女人
Photos. All of the same woman?
再看看这个
And look at this.
车牌号
License plate numbers.
起码几百个
Hundreds of them,
还有每辆车注册的地址
along with the registered address of each vehicle.
她怎么会有这些东西
Why would she have that?
看看这些车牌
Look at the plate numbers.
每个都有字母X和Z
Each one has the letters "X" And "Z" in it.
我们的受害者在找某个特定的人
Our victim was looking for someone specific.
对  但是谁呢
Yeah, but who?
我知道应该去问谁了
I think I know someone we can ask.
我就知道艾玛会出事
I knew something bad would happen to Emma.
我一直想找她  想阻止她
I was trying to find her, to -- to stop her.
马洛伊先生  你女儿究竟来纽约干什么
Mr. Malloy, what was your daughter doing in the city?
两个月前  她的一个朋友失踪了
Two months ago, a friend of hers disappeared.
艾玛想找到她
Emma was trying to find her.
等等
Wait.
这是她的朋友吗
Was this her friend?
是的  佐伊·艾迪森
Yeah. Zoey Addison.
你说她消失了是什么意思
And what exactly do you mean by "She disappeared"?
佐伊的男朋友打她
Zoey had a boyfriend that was beating on her.
所以她开了她男友的车想去艾玛那儿住
So she took his car and was on her way to stay with Emma.
但却没开到她那儿
But she never showed.
几天之后  警察发现车停在路旁
Couple days later, the cops found the car
车的散热器坏掉了
by the side of the road with a busted radiator...
但佐伊却不知所踪
But no sign of Zoey.
-他们和她的男朋友谈过吗  -谈过
- Did they talk to the boyfriend? - Oh, yeah.
但有不在场证据证实他离现场有两州之隔
But he was two states away with an alibi.
他报案说车被偷了
He reported the car stolen,
所以警方认为佐伊偷车在逃
so the cops just figured that Zoey was on the run
然后弃车跑了
and ditched it for another ride.
艾玛知道佐伊不会那样做
But Emma knew that Zoey wouldn't do that --
不会不辞而别
not without calling.
艾玛当时是收银员  她请了假
So Emma took a leave from her cashier's job
想去找她  重走她的路线
to try to find her, retracing her route.
艾玛在一个卡车休息站找到了目击者
Em found a waitress at a truck stop
那人看见佐伊坐进了一辆白色轿车
who saw Zoey get in the back of a white sedan.
那车是纽约牌照并且有字母X和Z
With New York plates containing the letters "X" And "Z"?
是的
Yeah.
那个女服务员告诉艾玛
The waitress told Emma it had an oval sticker
车后窗贴有椭圆的贴纸写着纽约市
in its back window that said "NYC."
她来纽约就是为了查这件事
That's what she was doing in the city.
她想找到佐伊上的那辆车
She was trying to track the car Zoey got into.
马洛伊先生这片树林能让你想起什么吗
Mr. Malloy, do these woods mean anything to you?
有什么原因会让艾玛去那吗
Is there any reason that Emma would be in them?
它们有没有可能在佐伊的路线上
Were they on Zoey's route, maybe?
离她失踪的地方近吗
Somewhere near where she disappeared?
佐伊来自匹兹堡  是相反的方向
Zoey was coming from Pittsburgh, the opposite direction.
这么长时间来  都没有她的消息吗
And all this time, no one's heard anything from her?
佐伊没有家人
Zoey didn't have family.
要不是艾玛
And if it wasn't for Emma,
根本没人知道她失踪的事
no one would have even known that she'd disappeared.
这就是为什么我找不到
That's why I could never find the girl
那个我在树林里看见的女孩
I saw in the woods.
他把目标锁定在那些不被在意的人身上
He targets people who won't be missed --
搭便车的旅行者  被困的司机
hitchhikers, stranded motorists.
问上几个问题
He asks them a couple of questions.
如果符合这个标准  他就会杀害他们
If they fit the profile, he kills them.
如果不是  他就只是个好心人带他们一程
And if not, he's just some good samaritan giving them a ride.
所以他才没有杀了我
That's why he didn't kill me.
那样会引起注意
It would have attracted attention.
三十年了
30 years.
你觉得他做了多少这样的事  10次
How many times do you think he did this? 10?
20次还是100次
20? 100?
我早就该想办法阻止他
I should have found a way to stop him.
卡塞尔  你当时才11岁
Castle, you were 11 years old.
并且当时发生在你身上的事情很糟糕
And what happened to you back then was terrible.
我理解你把这次案件
And I know that you're thinking of this case
当做是驱除恶魔的一种方式
as a way to exorcise those demons,
但我们还不知道我们面临的是什么
but we don't know what we have here.
我们甚至不知道这是不是同一人所为
We don't even know if this is the same person.
当然是同一个人
Of course it's the same person.
艾玛一定是做了我没有做的事
See, Emma must have been able to do what I never could.
她找到了这个人
She tracked him down.
这就是为什么他找上了艾玛
That's why he went after her.
我必须把这人找出来  凯特
I have to find this guy, Kate.
我得给这事画上句号
I need to end this.
伙计们  有没有什么办法
Guys, is there any way
能查到30年前的警方记录
to check police records from 30 years ago?
看有没有任何被丢弃的汽车
See if there were any abandoned cars
在霍兰德森林50英里范围内收到过罚单
ticketed within a 50-mile radius of Hollander's woods?
当然  我们只需要打给
Sure. We just have to call
那一地区的所有市政警察部门
all the municipal police departments in the area...
等着他们嘲笑完
And wait for them to stop laughing long enough
跪求他们去布满灰尘的储存室里找一找
to beg them to check their dusty storage rooms.
-你是认真的吗  -我们必须
- You serious? - We need to
知道我们现在面对的是怎样的情况
know exactly what we're dealing with here,
所以  二位纪念日愉快了
so happy manniversary.
贝克特探长  借一步说话
Detective Beckett. A word?
-关一下门  -好的
- Close the door. - Oh, yeah.
我刚接到总局的电话
I just got a call from 1pp.
他们想让我今晚放你的假
They want me to take you off shift tonight
去做绩效评估
for a performance review.
警监
Um, sir,
我的绩效评估是在三个月后
my review's not scheduled for another three months.
你觉得
D-do you think that this has something
这和警监的考试有关吗
to do with the captain's exam?
不会  他们不会要求会面讨论考试结果
No, they don't ask for a meet to discuss exam results.
那是发邮件通知你的
They notify you by mail.
那到底是怎么回事
So w-what's going on?
我不清楚  我认识的人都不知情
I don't know, and none of my sources are talking.
他们让你七点半赶到那
But they want you there at 7:30.
很有可能是好消息
Well, maybe it's good news.
也许你也得奖了
Maybe you're getting an award, too --
凶杀组杰出成就奖
"Career Achievement in Homicide."
好吧  也许也不是
Yeah, okay, it's probably not that.
但还是有可能是好消息
But, still, it could be good news.
那为什么我的警察直觉告诉我这是坏事
Well, then why is my cop sense telling me it's bad?
伙计们  有线索了
Hey, guys. Got something.
我在查艾玛清单上的列出车牌号
I was running those license plates on Emma's list,
看这些车主是否有犯罪史
seeing if any of the owners have criminal backgrounds,
我发现这辆车登记的地址
when I noticed this car registered to an address
和艾玛被杀害当天去过的那家咖啡店
right down the street from the coffee shop
在同一条街上
where Emma went the day she was killed.
她在监视那辆车
She was surveilling that car.
她肯定认为这辆车
She must have thought it was the one
就是佐伊在卡车休息站上的那辆车
that Zoey got into at the truck stop.
当这辆车的车主意识到艾玛在追查他时
And when the owner of the car realized she was onto him,
-他就找上了她  -这是谁的车
- he went after her. - Whose car is it?
这就是奇怪的地方  车主是这名女性
That's the weird thing. It belongs to this woman.
康妮·刘易斯
Connie Lewis.
她已经72岁并且没有犯罪记录
But she's 72 and has no criminal record.
她的地址是什么
What's her address?
就是这了
There it is.
白色轿车  车牌有X和Z
White sedan, "X" And "Z" in the plate,
车窗上有纽约市的贴纸
"NYC" Sticker in the window.
就和艾玛找到的目击者描述的一样
Exactly as Emma's witness described.
但是一个72岁的女性
Yeah, but how's a 72-year-old woman
怎么会和这一切有关呢
connected to all of this?
你还好吗
You okay?
这么多年了  我也许终于要得到答案了
After all these years, I may finally get some answers.
刘易斯太太
Mrs. Lewis?
纽约警察
NYPD.
门没锁
It's open.
电视开着
TV's on.
刘易斯夫人  能听见吗
Mrs. Lewis, can you hear me?!
刘易斯夫人
Mrs. Lewis?
表面并没有外伤
There were no outward signs of trauma
皮肤上也没有伤痕
or carvings in her skin.
但在我回去给她验尸之前
But until I get her back to the morgue,
还不能排除谋杀的可能
we can't rule out homicide.
她死了多长时间了
How long has she been dead?
根据腐烂程度  我想应该有三年了
Based on decay, I'd say about three years.
怎么会没人发现呢
How did no one notice?
凶手发现了  所以用了她的车
The killer did, and he used her car.
或许还用了她家
And maybe her place.
看看我在厨房里发现了什么
Look what I found in the kitchen.
和我们在艾玛酒店房间里发现的火柴盒一样
The same matchbook that we found in Emma's hotel room.
如果艾玛在跟踪凶手
If Emma was tailing the killer,
她可能跟着他去过那里
she could have followed him there.
我找到了刘易斯的亲属
I tracked down Lewis' next of kin.
唯一的亲人是她儿子
Only family listed is a son.
在她的东西里找到了他的号码
Found this number for him in her things.
区号是910  是哪的
910 area code? Where's that from?
-北卡罗来纳州  -好的
- North Carolina. - Okay.
我来通知他  看看他知道些什么
I'll handle the notification, see what he knows.
都三年没见了  肯定知道的不多
Not much, if he hasn't seen her in three years.
他这做儿子的怎么三年都不来看他母亲
What kind of a son doesn't check on his own mother?
不是所有的家庭和和睦相处的
Not all families get along.
我父亲有二十多年没跟他兄弟说过一句话
My father didn't talk to his brother for 20 years.
是空的
It's empty.
检查一下电话
Check for the phone.
被移动过
It's been moved.
里面的人  把武器放下
You inside, drop your weapon!
地上有个洞
There's a hole in the floor.
各位  他在下面  我们走
You guys, he's below us. Let's go!
诺亚·刘易斯  52岁
Noah Lewis. 52.
90年代时在部队打杂工
He did a stint in the army back in the '90s.
最近一段时间没有工作记录
There's no recent records about employment.
他跟邻居说他母亲卧床不起
He told the neighbors that his mother was bedridden
由他来照顾
and that he was taking care of her.
所以他们觉得他是个孝顺儿子
So they just assumed that he was the good son.
是的  不过他们的关系很不好
Yeah, but the relationship was far from rosy.
四年前  他母亲把他送进了
Four years ago, his mother had him committed
一家州立精神病院
to a state mental institution
起因是他用刀威胁她
after he threatened her with a knife.
所以我跟当时受指派医治他的医生
So I got in touch with the state-appointed shrink
取得了联系
who's treating him.
他说诺亚有边缘型人格障碍
he says that Noah has borderline personality disorder
伴有暴力倾向
and exhibited violent tendencies.
那就是他了
So it's him.
有没有记录显示他三十年前在哪里
Any record of where he was 30 years ago?
我们更关注的是他现在在哪
Well, we're a little bit more focused on where he is now.
有几队人正在附近搜索
We have teams still combing the neighborhood.
也发了通告  可到目前什么都没查到
We put out a BOLO. But so far, nothing.
你对凶手作案模式的看法好像真对了
Your theory about the killer's M.O. may have just paid off.
你发现什么了吗
You found something?
是的  1983年的二月份
Yeah, from February of '83.
在你发现那具尸体的第二天
The day after you saw that body,
警察给一辆遗弃的皮卡车贴了罚单
police ticketed an abandoned pickup truck
车是在霍兰德森林附近的路边被发现的
they saw by the roadside near Hollander's Woods.
那辆车的主人是个农民
The truck belonged to a farmer
把车借给了一个来工作的年轻女移民
who'd loaned it to a young woman, a migrant worker,
她要外出买点东西
to go out and make a supply run.
当警察通知那个农民找到了他的车时
When the cops told the farmer that they'd found his truck,
他只是以为她逃走了
he assumed that she'd just run off.
所以他也没报失踪
So he never reported her missing.
是的  他不想跟移民局惹上麻烦
No. He didn't want to get her in trouble with immigration.
他还记得那个女人是谁吗
Did he remember who she was?
是的
Yeah.
他还有一张照片
And he had a photo.
她叫什么名字
What was her name?
罗莎莉塔·坎波
Rosalita Campo.
我们会再查一下诺亚
We'll dig deeper into Noah,
看看他在三十年前跟那个地方有没有交集
see if we can connect him to that area 30 years ago.
我们会找到他的  卡塞尔
We'll find him, Castle.
我保证
I promise.
我要去进行评估了
I'm supposed to head off to my review.
你需要我推迟一下吗
Do you want me to postpone?
不用  我应该跟你一起去的
No. I should go with you.
我一个人能行
I'll be all right.
结束后我会打给你  好吗
I'll call you when I'm done, okay?
好的
Okay.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
你在忙吗  我可以
Are you busy? I can...
没有  我只是
No, I was just...
在看一些我很久前写的东西
reading something I wrote a long time ago.
老爸  你知道的时候有多大
Dad, how old were you when you knew?
知道什么
Knew what?
你想成为一名作家
That you wanted to be a writer.
我想是在小时候吧  怎么了
Since I was a kid, I guess. Why?
我马上就要上完大三了
I'm finishing my junior year,
可我还不知道我想做什么
and I have no idea what I want to do.
你在我这个年龄的时候
By the time you were my age,
已经出版了你的第一本书了
you'd already published your first book,
现在你因为做了自己非常喜欢的事
And now you're winning this amazing award
而赢了这个了不起的大奖
because you followed your passion.
如果我找不到自己喜欢的事
How can I be amazing
怎么能成为了不起的人呢
if I can't find mine?
相信我
Trust me.
你会找到的
You will.
或者
Or...
它会找到你
or it'll find you.
总有一天  你回过头来看看
And one day, you will look back,
你就会发现
and you will realize that...
你的每个经历
every experience you ever had,
每次错误  每次失败
every seeming mistake or blind alley,
都帮助你走向了
was actually a straight line
你应该成为的那个人
to who you were meant to be.
而无论你成为什么样的人  我都毫不怀疑
And whatever you become, there's no question in my mind
你会让人刮目相看的
You are going to be amazing.
你明白我是怎么知道的吗
And you know how I know?
怎么
How?
因为你已经让人刮目相看了
'cause you already are.
他们已经在等你了  探长
They're ready for you, Detective.
请坐
Take a seat.
贝克特探长
So, Detective Beckett,
这上面说你参加了警监考核
Says here you took the captain's exam.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
是什么使你觉得你符合做警监的条件
What you makes you think you're qualified to be captain?
我在12分局的经历
My experience in the 12th precinct
使我熟悉了从领导角度工作
has made me comfortable in a leadership position,
-而现在...  -我想问的是...
- and at this point -- - What I mean is...
是什么使你觉得你甚至可以胜任
What makes you think you're even qualified
纽约警局探长的工作
to be an NYPD detective?
长官
Sir?
你的工作职责是执法
Your job is to enforce the law,
然而你却多次藐视法律
yet you have repeatedly ignored it.
在洛杉矶  你调查了一起
In Los Angeles, you investigated a case
-不属于你管辖的案件  -但是...
- outside of your legal jurisdiction. - But --
利用你的职权向布莱肯议员
You used your badge to pursue a personal vendetta
报私仇  跨过法律界限
against Senator Bracken, crossing the line
无数次置他人生命于危险
and endangering the lives of others numerous times.
长官  那个人是杀人犯
Sir, that man was a murderer.
你曾经向上级隐瞒案件信息
You've withheld case information from superiors
只要愿意就公然蔑视当局权威
and flown in the face of authority whenever it suits you,
更不要说你和理查德·卡塞尔的工作关系
not to mention your working relationship with Richard Castle.
告诉我  探长  你有多少次
Tell me, Detective, how often have you let
因你对你丈夫的私人感情
your personal feelings for your husband
左右了你追捕嫌犯的行动
dictate your actions in pursuit of a suspect?
长官  你说的不对  我从没有...
Sir, that is unfair. I never let --
当他失踪之后  你利用职权
And when he went missing, you used your position
和大量纳税人的钱
and a great deal of the taxpayers' money
以及同僚警探们的帮助来搜寻他
to search for him, enlisting the aid of fellow detectives.
而且  你早就臭名昭著了  因为你是
And, well, you are infamous for being the inspiration
虚构的纽约警局探长妮基·希特的原型
for the fictional NYPD detective Nikki Heat,
你和她一样  不干正事的时间
who spends more time on her back
比追捕嫌犯的时间还要多
than she does pursuing killers.
贝克特探长  你凭什么领导别人
Detective Beckett, how do you expect to lead
或是继续干你现在这份工作
or even continue in your current job
很明显你经常做出错误的判断
when it's clear you've exercised such poor judgment?
长官  如果你看过我的档案...
Sir, if you would look at my record --
我们现在就看着呢
We are looking at your record.
你根本没有做警监的资格
You are not qualified for a captaincy,
在我看来...
and in my opinion...
你连做探长的资格都没有
You are not qualified to be a detective.
谢谢  你可以走了
Thank you. You can go.
你说错了  长官
You're wrong, sir.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我说  "你说错了"
I said, "You're wrong."
你看过的每一个案件
In every case you have referenced,
我不仅成功地把凶手捉拿归案
I have not only successfully brought the killer to justice,
更是怀着对法律  对我所代表的警局
but I did so with the utmost respect for the law
最深的敬意
and for the department I represent.
至于我和卡塞尔先生的关系
And regarding my relationship with Mr. Castle,
事实证明他是个非常出色的搭档
He has proven to be a brilliant partner
而且他总是支持着我
and he's always had my back.
至于他以我虚构出的角色
And as for his...fictional representation of me,
我很自豪能够成为他的灵感来源
I'm proud to have been his inspiration,
作为他的妻子我也很骄傲
and I am proud to be his wife.
你问我  "我凭什么领导别人"
You asked, "How do I expect to lead?"
就凭我只做正确的事情
By continuing to fight for what's right,
而不是做简单的事情
not for what's easy.
我工作的职责是保护纽约的市民
My job is to protect the citizens of New York,
我会比其他所有人都要努力做好这份工作
and I will do it by doing my job better than anyone else
并取得成果
and getting results.
我从不越过界限
I don't cross the line.
我把自己至于界限之上
I put myself on it.
如果你还有什么问题的话
And if you have any other questions,
那你可以去问问那些
then you can ask the families
我帮助过的被害人家属
of the victims that I have served.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
请坐
Sit down.
那真是个慷慨有力的回答
That was an impassioned and powerful response.
事实上  这也正是我们期望看到的
In fact, it was exactly what we were hoping for.
这其实并不是表现评估
This wasn't a performance review.
那你为什么要像那样攻击我
Then why would you attack me like that?
我们想看看你能否为自己辩护
We wanted to see if you could defend yourself.
凯特  这是个测试
Kate, this was an audition.
为什么测试
For what?
为你的未来
Your future.
我们一直在找像你一样的人...
We've been looking for someone like you --
像你一样不会被收买的
Someone who isn't corruptible,
一个人们可以支持的公众英雄
a certifiable hero who the people can get behind.
凯特  你的舞台比你现在做的要更宽广
Kate, you're bigger than what you're doing now.
你也知道的
You know it.
这也是你去华盛顿以及参加警监考核的原因
It's why you went to D.C., why you took the captain's exam.
你想要一个更大的舞台
You want a bigger stage,
我们也想给你一个
and we want to give it to you.
我们觉得你的未来一片光明
We think you have an amazing future.
做什么呢
Doing what?
我们想让你竞选纽约州参议员
We'd like you to run for New York State Senate.
州参议员
State Senator?
他们说这还只是个开始
And they say it's just the start.
他们好像关注我已经有一段时间了
Apparently the party has had their eye on me for a while now.
他们认为大家想找像我这样的人
They think that people are looking for someone like me.
那你有什么想法
And what do you think?
我不知道  卡塞尔
I don't know, Castle.
我是个警察  不是政客
I'm a cop, not a politician.
我有没有跟你说过
Did I ever tell you
我小时候曾经参加过模拟联合国
that I was in a model U.N. when I was a kid?
有次我妈担任在场监护人
My mom was one of the chaperones.
看过我的表现后  她说"你知道吗  小凯"
And after watching me, she said, "You know, Katie...
你长大之后想做什么都可以
You can grow up and be anything you want."
我想成为和她一样的人
I just wanted to be her.
想像她一样做出一番事业
I just wanted to make a difference.
你已经做到了
And you have.
现在的问题是  你能否做得更大
The question now is, can you make a bigger difference?
卡塞尔  如果你看到了
Castle, if you saw the way
他们在里面是如何奚落我的...
that they attacked me in that room...
等竞选时  只会变本加厉
And in a campaign, it would only be worse.
你  阿丽克西斯  我父亲  玛莎
You, Alexis, my dad, Martha,
你们都会成为被攻击的对象
you guys would all be fair game.
我们可都是意志坚强的人
We're a tough bunch.
那你觉得我能竞选吗
So you think I could do it?
我相信你可以
I know you can.
他们说我高分通过了警监考核
They said that I aced my captain's exam.
估计一年之内我就可以管理自己的分局了
I could probably have my own precinct within the year.
什么时候需要答复
When do you have to decide?
很快
Soon.
不管你如何决定
Well, whatever you decide...
我都支持你
I will back your play.
谢谢
Thank you.
火柴盒的线索有收获了
That matchbook lead paid off.
派去监视酒吧的警员
The unit that we put on that bar
发现了诺亚·刘易斯
spotted Noah Lewis heading inside.
刚刚缉捕了他
E.S.U. just took him down.
找到他了
They found him.
我妈妈呢
Where's my mother?
尸检中
Being autopsied.
我警告过她
I warned her,
但她就是唠叨不停
but she wouldn't stop running her mouth at me.
现在唠叨不成了吧
Now she doesn't say a word.
瞧瞧她的下场
It's what she deserved.
那其他人呢
Well, what about the others?
她们也活该吗
Did they deserve what they got?
我们已经知道你的所作所为了  诺亚
We know what you've done, Noah...
知道了你的真面目
Who you really are.
讲讲艾玛·马洛伊的事
Tell us about Emma Malloy.
光说名字想不起来
I'm not good with names.
你见过她
You know her.
前天晚上你在哪
Where were you the night before last?
-外面  -外面哪
- Out. - Out where?
邻居说你的车不在
Neighbors said your car was gone.
开车兜风去了
I took a drive.
是开去森林了吗
Did you drive to the woods?
那这个女孩呢  佐伊·艾迪森
What about this girl? Zoey Addison.
有人看到她上了你的车  诺亚
She was seen getting into your car, Noah.
现在失踪了
Now she's gone.
挺漂亮的
Mm. She's pretty.
她死了吗
Is she dead?
我不知道
I can't help you.
你把她们都带去哪里了  其他人
Where do you take them, the others?
你是怎么让她们失踪的
How do you make them disappear?
我们有你的车  诺亚  还可以调查你的房子
We have your car, Noah, your house.
总会找到证据的
We will find evidence.
艾玛是不是发现了什么证据
Did Emma find evidence?
所以你才杀了她吗
Is that why you went after her?
因为她接近了真相
Because she got too close?
所以你才向我们开枪吗
Is that why you shot at us?
你们进了我家
You were in my house.
还看不出吗
Don't you see?
我才是受害者
I'm the victim here.
I'm the victim.
怎么了
What's wrong?
他逍遥法外了三十多年
Just he's been getting away with it for 30 years.
我本以为他会更...骇人一些
I thought he'd be more... formidable.
有麻烦了
We have a problem.
刚得到鉴证组的消息
I just spoke with C.S.U.
目前还未在房中车中发现任何可以证明
So far, they haven't found anything in the house or the car
诺亚和艾玛或佐伊有关联的证据
that links Noah to Emma or Zoey.
就是说我们没法证明他和那些谋杀案的联系
So we can't connect him to either of their murders?
那他妈妈的死呢
What about his mother's?
尸检结果
Autopsy results
表明她是自然死亡
indicate that she died of natural causes.
现在  他的罪名只有不当处理尸体
Right now, all we have this guy on is mishandling a body.
-他冲我们开枪了  -是  但当时他在衣橱里
- He shot at us. - Yeah, but he was hiding in the closet at the time.
他可以说不知道我们是警察  可以脱罪的
He can claim he didn't know we were cops. He can plead out.
卡塞尔  我们都没法证明他和霍兰德森林的关系
Castle, we can't even link this guy to Hollander's Woods.
83年  他在南卡罗来纳州的
In '83, he was at a military academy
一所军校上学
all the way in South Carolina.
当时是总统日的周末
It was Presidents' day weekend.
也许他在休假  或者逃学了
He could have been on vacation or -- or just skipping school.
但这些记录没有了  所以没法证明
Except those records are gone, so there's no way to prove it.
陪审团能看到的只是
All the jury's gonna hear is that he was
他当时离新罕布什尔一1000英里
1,000 miles away from New Hampshire.
没有证据  我们就没法立案
Without evidence, we don't have a case.
本案的关键在于艾玛
The key to this is Emma.
我们得证明
We need to place his car
她被袭前后他的车在附近
in the area at the time she was attacked.
和柯林斯合作  在那里取证
Let's coordinate with Collins and set up a canvass up there.
总该有个他常去的地方
There's got to be a place he goes --
一个偏僻的用来抛尸的地方
somewhere out of the way where he puts the bodies.
你说他有个心理医生
You said that he was seeing a shrink.
没错  范·霍茨曼医生
Yeah. A, uh -- a Dr. Van Holtzman.
也许诺亚的心理咨询中有说过什么
You know, maybe Noah said something during his sessions
有助破案的线索
that could help us.
去哪找霍茨曼
Where do we find Holtzman?
如果诺亚被无罪释放
If Noah ends up walking,
你恐怕得把我弄进精神病院
you're gonna have to have me committed.
打扰
Excuse me.
我们想见一下霍茨曼医生  谢谢
We need to speak with Dr. Holtzman, please.
当然  请稍等
Of course. Just a moment.
这七年来你的无数疯狂理论
Listen, if after seven years of your crazy theories,
都没让你走火入魔
you haven't already been committed,
我觉得心理医生还是免了
then I think you're pretty safe.
你好  我是霍茨曼医生
Hi. I'm Dr. Holtzman.
听说你们要找我
I understand you've been looking for me.
我是贝克特警探
Yeah, I'm Detective Beckett.
这位是理查德·卡塞尔
This is Richard Castle.
我们需要就你的
We need to speak with you
患者诺亚·刘易斯  问你几个问题
regarding one of your patients -- Noah Lewis.
当然可以
Of course.
请允许我先处理这几个处方
Let me just finish with these prescriptions,
然后就来见你们
and I'll be right with you.
好的
Okay.
贝克特  我认出了他的声音
Beckett, I know that voice --
就是那天霍兰德森林里那个人的声音
from that day in Hollander's Woods.
是他  他才是凶手
It's him. He's the killer.
卡塞尔  那都是三十年前的事了
Castle, that was over 30 years ago.
-你不可能  -凯特  他说话时
- You can't possibly -- - Kate, when he spoke,
我都能想起刀抵在我喉咙上的感觉
I could feel the knife at my throat.
我死也忘不了那个声音
I will never forget that voice as long as I live.
抱歉耽搁了
Sorry about that.
我们去我办公室谈吧
Shall we talk in my office?
请坐
Please, have a seat.
我得说听说了诺亚做的事
I wish I could say that I was surprised
我并不惊讶
to hear what Noah had done.
但他确实深受困扰
But he was very troubled.
他在这里接受治疗时我们竭尽了全力
We did everything we could for him while he was in our care.
霍茨曼医生  你治疗刘易斯先生多久了
Dr. Holtzman, how long have you been treating Mr. Lewis?
四年了
Four years.
他母亲送他来后  我们一度稳定了他的病情
We got him stable after his mother committed him,
但放他出院的条件之一就是
but a condition of his release
每月的法定治疗
were state-mandated sessions every month.
你们俩都聊了些什么
And what did the two of you talk about?
愤怒  亲密  他对女人的敌意
Anger, intimacy, his animosity toward women.
你是达特茅斯毕业的
You went to Dartmouth.
是的  本科
Yes, for undergrad.
你上一次见到刘易斯先生是什么时候
Uh, when was the last time you saw Mr. Lewis?
几天前
A few days ago.
他相当焦虑
He was quite agitated.
他觉得有人跟踪他
He thought someone was following him.
我以为他只是有妄想症
I thought he was just being paranoid,
所以调整了他的用药
so I adjusted his meds.
你完全不知道他会有暴力行为
And you had no idea that he was about to do something violent?
不知道
None.
他以前也干过这种事
He's done this before, you know.
绑架女人  在树林里杀了她们
Abducted women, killed them in the woods --
可能持续了好几年
possibly for years.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
有目击者
Witnesses.
他作案时带着面具
When he does it, he wears a mask.
他为什么这么做  在杀人时带上面具
Now, why would he do that -- wear a mask when he kills them?
-我不知道  -试着猜猜看
- I don't know. - If you had to guess.
什么样的精神疾病会促使一个人这么做
What kind of psychosis would drive a man to do that?
可怕的童年吗
Something terrible in his childhood?
精神变态者的心理可没那么简单
The mind of a psychopath is not that simple.
但他还是杀了她们
But he kills them anyway.
那他为什么要把脸藏在这副面具之下呢
So why would he need to hide his face behind this?
也许他不是在隐藏
Maybe he's not hiding it.
也许这才是他真正的脸
Maybe this is his true face...
他内心深处的怪物
the monster he knows he really is.
他希望被害者
And he wants his victims
在临死前看到它  畏惧它
to see it and fear it before they die.
也许他真正的面具
Maybe his real mask
是他每天都伪装成的那个人
is the man he has to pretend to be every day.
他的声音
His voice?
我知道  这听上去很疯狂
I know. It sounds crazy.
因为它就是很疯狂  卡塞尔
Because it is, Castle.
我们已经有一个嫌疑犯了
We already have a suspect.
他很有嫌疑
Ah, the perfect suspect.
因为霍茨曼医生了解他病人的
Because Dr. Holtzman knew intimate details
隐私  他陷害诺亚为他顶罪
about his patients, he set Noah up to take the fall
以防有人查到那些谋杀案
just in case anyone got onto the murders.
而且霍茨曼1983年时在新罕布什尔州
And Holtzman was in New Hampshire, at Dartmouth,
达特茅斯学院
in 1983.
他是个居家好男人  结婚24年
He's a family man, married to his wife for 24 years.
有孩子  非常受人尊敬  从未被逮捕过
Kids, well-respected, never been arrested.
还有目击者
And witnesses.
他们看见被害人上了诺亚的车
They saw the victim get into Noah's car,
而不是霍茨曼的
not Holtzman's.
那件事我还无法解释  但是
I can't explain that yet, but...
霍茨曼是幕后黑手
Holtzman is behind this, and...
宝贝  那个声音  有没有可能是你记错了
Babe, the voice -- is it possible you're misremembering?
你把这个杀手魔鬼化了
You've made this killer your personal bogeyman.
你自己也说过
You said so yourself.
你希望他更骇人一些
You wanted him to be more formidable.
你们不相信我
You don't believe me.
他是清白的
He's clean.
他和这桩案件没有关系
He has no connection to this case.
我们没有线索继续追查
We've got nothing to go on.
比没有还要少
Less than nothing.
我们只有一个30年前的声音指认
All we have is a 30-year-old voice I.D.
况且目击者在案发时还是个孩子
from a witness who was a kid at the time.
卡塞尔  我们和你一样想破案
Look, Castle, we want to solve it as much as you do.
你知道吗
You know what?
我料到这些人会不相信我
I expected this from these guys.
但我没料到你也如此
Just not from you.
卡塞尔
Castle.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你说是他  我相信你
You said it was him. I believe you.
但你说得对
Except you're right.
我们什么也做不了
There's nothing we can do.
我们得盯梢他好几年  等他再次出手
We'd have to sit on him for years, hoping he makes a move.
这不是故事应有的结局
This is not how the story was supposed to end.
我在想
I was thinking.
他是如何让被害者无声无息地消失的呢
How did he make those victims disappear without a trace?
他一定得把她们带到某个地方
Well, he would have had to have taken them somewhere.
某个他的家人不知道的地方
Somewhere his family didn't know about.
他一定有个老巢  一个贮藏室
He'd have to have a lair, a storage space somewhere.
那就有太多危险了
Too many things could go wrong.
比如洪水  再比如爱管闲事的管理人员
There could be a flood, a nosy manager.
他必须找一个
He would have to find a place
他可以完全掌控的地方
over which he had absolute control.
所以我做了个资产调查
So I did a property search.
他名下什么也没有  但我找到了这个
It came up empty on him, but I did find this.
-农场  -是啊
- Farmland? - Yeah.
产权归霍茨曼去世的父母所有
Owned by Holtzman's parents, both deceased.
在一份信托中
It's in a trust.
霍茨曼被列为唯一的受托人
Holtzman is listed as the sole trustee.
他的妻子有可能不知道
It's possible his wife doesn't know about it.
这距离艾玛被卡车撞倒的地方只有几英里
It's only a few miles from where Emma was hit by that truck.
税收记录显示这个地产上有座谷仓
Tax records show that there's a barn on the property.
他一定把她关在那儿了
He must have held her there.
那是私人地产  又荒无人烟
It's private, in the middle of nowhere.
最佳隐蔽场所
The perfect lonely place.
只是  我永远也拿不到搜索令
Only, I would never get a warrant.
如果没有搜索令去搜查的话
And if I searched it without one,
我找到的任何证据都不会被许可
then any evidence I would find would be inadmissible.
因为你是个警察
'cause you're a cop.
但你不是
But you're not.
这是非法入侵
It would be trespassing.
你会违法的
You would be breaking the law.
但如果你找到了线索
But if you found something...
我知道这对你来说意义重大
And I know how much this means to you,
所以不管你的决定如何  我都支持你
so whatever you decide, I will back your play.
看上去荒废很久了
Looks deserted.
这是地产分割线
This is the property line.
你应该待在这边
You should stay back here on this side.
好吧  但你不能单独进去
Okay, but you're not going in alone.
打开免提
Keep me on speaker.
告诉我你找到了什么
Let me know what you find.
好
Right.
你看见什么了
So, what are you seeing?
他好像将谷仓用作贮藏
Looks like he uses it for storage.
恐怖  恐怖的贮藏
Creepy, creepy storage.
贝克特  这有一辆和诺亚一样的车
Beckett, it's the same car that Noah has.
同样的颜色
Same color...
同样的车牌  同样的标志  一模一样
Same license plate, same sticker -- everything.
他就是这么干的
That's how he did it.
如果有人看到他  就会追查到诺亚
So if someone spotted him, it would lead right back to Noah.
但你需要更多线索才能报警
But you're gonna need more than that to call the police.
四处看看
Look around.
他可能保留了被害人的物件当做战利品
He may have kept trophies from his victims.
你还好吗
You okay?
是的
Yeah.
上帝啊
Oh, god.
卡塞尔
Castle?
卡塞尔  你看到了什么
Castle, what do you see now?
我看到了她们
I see them.
被害者的照片
Photos of his victims.
都在这
I see all of them.
贝克特  他在这  他在屋里
Beckett, he's here. He's inside.
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
自霍兰德森林的事之后  我一直在找你
I've been looking for you since Hollander's Woods.
那男孩
The boy.
是你
That was you?
当时我应该杀了你
I should have killed you when I had the chance.
你赢不了的  霍茨曼
You can't win, Holtzman.
我们知道你是谁
We know who you are.
无所谓
It doesn't matter.
你俩都会死
You're both be dead.
他们永远找不到我
And they'll never find me.
卡塞尔
Castle!
被锁住了
It's locked!
-贝克特  -卡塞尔
- Beckett! - Castle!
我进不去
I can't get in!
面对心魔的危险是
The danger of facing your demons...
...有时  心魔会战胜你
...is that sometimes the demons win.
卡塞尔  发生了什么
Castle, what's going on in there?!
卡塞尔
Castle!
贝克特
Beckett!
天啊
God!
-你还好吗  还好吗  -还好
- Are you okay? You okay? - Yeah.
著名心理学家范·霍茨曼乡下住所
Still more gruesome discoveries and many more questions
发现了更多可怖物证  留下更多不解谜题
at the rural property of noted psychologist Van Holtzman
当局仍在寻找
as authorities continue
被其埋藏的被害者尸体
to find the buried bodies of his victims.
我以为你要练习今晚的演讲
Thought you were practicing your speech for tonight.
是的
Oh, yeah. I was.
只是...
I just, um...
我不禁在想
I couldn't help but wonder --
如果不是他  不是那天树林里发生的事
If it wasn't for him, for that day in the woods,
我会成为现在的我吗
would I even be here?
我们会相遇吗
Would we be here?
宝贝  我们相识相知不是因为他
Babe, we're not here because of him.
我们拥有彼此是因为面对他这样的人  成就了我们
We're here because of who we are in the face of people like him.
所以你成为悬疑小说家
That's why you write mysteries.
所以我成为警察
That's why I became a cop.
我们都试图伸张正义
We're both trying to bring justice to this world.
现在
Now...
我去换衣服
...I'm gonna go and get dressed
以便到时我可以好好地为真实的你而骄傲
so I can be very proud tonight of who you are.
谋杀  悬疑  恐怖与死亡
Murder, mystery, the macabre --
今晚的得奖人样样精通
Tonight's honoree has mastered them all.
多年来  他以销魂的文笔
For years, he's kept his readers under his spell
深深地勾住读者的兴趣
with his electrifying prose.
我很荣幸地将
I'm very proud to present this year's recipient
坡之笔成就奖
of the Poe's Pen Career Achievement Award,
颁给我的好友理查德·卡塞尔
my good friend Richard Castle.
女士们先生们  迈克尔·康奈利
Michael Connelly, ladies and gentlemen.
非常感谢  迈克尔
Thank you very much, Michael.
感谢你们颁这个奖给我
And my thanks to all of you for this honor.
我...
You know, I-I...
过去这几天  我一直在想
I've spent a lot of time the last few days
我是如何走到这一步的
thinking about how I got here.
无尽的赶稿  停不住的灵感枯竭
The long hours, the blank pages.
很多人认为写作是份孤独的职业
Most people think that writing is a solitary profession,
我们窝在屋里  沉浸在想象世界
that we spend our days in our imaginary worlds...
打斗  恋爱  死去
fighting, loving, dying.
但我们不是孤军奋战
But we don't do it alone...
因为我们所写的佳作来源于真实
Because anything that's good in our writing comes from truth.
事实是
And the truth is,
我走到这一步是因为我生命中的贵人
I'm here because of the people in my life.
母亲
Mother.
在我眼中  你永远是明星
You will always be a star in my eyes.
阿丽克西斯  你每天都让我赞叹
And, Alexis, you amaze me every day.
你俩是我无条件之爱的两根红发支柱
You two are my redheaded pillars of unconditional love.
12分局的朋友们
To my friends at the 12th precinct...
你们容纳了我
You let me in.
尤其是哈维尔和凯文
Especially you two, Javier, Kevin.
你们把我当成并肩作战的兄弟
You've made me your brother-in-arms,
为此  感谢你们
and I thank you for that.
凯特
And Kate.
七年前  我以为我再也写不下去了
Seven years ago, I thought I would never write again.
结果你走进了大门
And then you walked through the door.
我的世界就此改变
And my whole world changed.
你是对的  你曾说"我什么都不知道"
You were right -- you said I had no idea.
但我现在知道了
But now I do.
这是因为你
This is because of you.
因为我们
Because of us.
永远
Always.
演讲很感人  亲爱的
That was a lovely speech, darling.
我有被启发
Oh, well, I was inspired.
卡塞尔  如果贝克特成了议员
Castle, who's gonna be your inspiration
谁会成为你的灵感之源
if Beckett becomes state senator?
对啊  你就不能跟在她身后转悠了
Yeah, you won't be able to follow her around anymore.
我不清楚
Oh, I don't know.
也许下部写政治惊悚
Maybe I'll write a political thriller next.
我有兴趣拜读
I would so read that.
贝克特  如果你竞选  我帮你
Beckett, if you do run, I'll help with your campaign.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是很重要的决定  凯特
That's a pretty big step, Kate.
你想好了吗
Have you decided what you're going to do?
还没  不管怎么做
Not yet, but whatever it is,
我很向往前方的冒险
I'm looking forward to the adventure.
有件事可以确定  一切将会改变
One thing's for sure -- things are gonna change.
有件事不会变
Well, I know one thing that will never change --
我们都有的东西
What we all have.
祝酒
A toast.
敬我们
To us.
-敬我们  -敬我们  -敬我们
- To us. - To us. - To us.
干杯
Cheers.
是分局
It's the precinct.
有谋杀案
There's been a murder.
什么
What?